<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sonus Sundar - Full-stack Software Engineer</title><link>https://sonus.xyz/en/</link><description>Recent content on Sonus Sundar - Full-stack Software Engineer</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2025 05:50:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sonus.xyz/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Scaling Bitmasking: Mastering Permissions Beyond 64 Bits with Multiple Masks</title><link>https://sonus.xyz/en/blog/scaling-bitmasking-multiple-masks/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2025 05:50:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://sonus.xyz/en/blog/scaling-bitmasking-multiple-masks/</guid><description>Remember our last chat about how bitmasking can rescue your heavy JWTs? (If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read it yet, you can catch up on the basics and benefits here: &amp;ldquo;Fixing Heavy JWTs: Bitmasking for Lean &amp;amp; Scalable Permissions&amp;rdquo;). We saw how a single 64-bit integer could compactly represent up to 64 distinct permissions, slashing your token size from hefty kilobytes down to a few hundred bytes. That&amp;rsquo;s a game-changer!
But what if you&amp;rsquo;re building a massive system with hundreds, or even thousands, of super-granular permissions across multiple modules or services?</description></item><item><title>Fixing Heavy JWTs: Bitmasking for Lean &amp; Scalable Permissions</title><link>https://sonus.xyz/en/page/fix-heavy-jwts-bitmasking-scalable-permissions/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sonus.xyz/en/page/fix-heavy-jwts-bitmasking-scalable-permissions/</guid><description>Ever hit a wall with an error message that just screams, &amp;ldquo;Dude, you&amp;rsquo;re sending too much data!&amp;rdquo; Or maybe your shiny, new Single Page Application (SPA) suddenly starts acting weird, requests dropping like flies? Yeah, I&amp;rsquo;ve been there. For us, the culprit turned out to be our good old friend, the JSON Web Token (JWT), specifically when it got absolutely packed with permissions and claims. What started as a neat, efficient way to handle authorization quickly spiraled into a monster that was literally too big for its britches.</description></item><item><title>Fixing Heavy JWTs: Bitmasking for Lean &amp; Scalable Permissions</title><link>https://sonus.xyz/en/blog/fix-heavy-jwts-bitmasking-scalable-permissions/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2025 04:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://sonus.xyz/en/blog/fix-heavy-jwts-bitmasking-scalable-permissions/</guid><description>Ever hit a wall with an error message that just screams, &amp;ldquo;Dude, you&amp;rsquo;re sending too much data!&amp;rdquo; Or maybe your shiny, new Single Page Application (SPA) suddenly starts acting weird, requests dropping like flies? Yeah, I&amp;rsquo;ve been there. For us, the culprit turned out to be our good old friend, the JSON Web Token (JWT), specifically when it got absolutely packed with permissions and claims. What started as a neat, efficient way to handle authorization quickly spiraled into a monster that was literally too big for its britches.</description></item><item><title>Importance of Trailing Commas in Modern Development</title><link>https://sonus.xyz/en/blog/trailing-coma-and-programming/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sonus.xyz/en/blog/trailing-coma-and-programming/</guid><description>The Importance of Trailing Commas in Modern Development As a senior developer, I&amp;rsquo;ve seen how small practices can make a big difference in code maintenance and collaboration. One such practice is the use of trailing commas in our code. While it might seem like a minor detail, trailing commas offer several benefits that can significantly improve our development workflow.
Why Trailing Commas Matter Maintaining Git Blame Logs
One of the primary reasons to use trailing commas is to maintain clean and accurate git blame logs.</description></item><item><title>About Me</title><link>https://sonus.xyz/en/page/about/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sonus.xyz/en/page/about/</guid><description>2022-02-13 I am a curious programmer who loves to learn about something interesting.
Professional Summary Accomplished Software Developer offering 11 years&amp;rsquo; experience in comprehensive design and development of infrastructure and architecture for software projects. Attentive collaborator and communicator from project conception to completion. Creative in devising solutions to improve business operations and meet clients&amp;rsquo; technical needs. Seasoned team leader possessing the technical and interpersonal skills to provide exceptional project deliverables.</description></item><item><title>RegEx for parsing chemical formulas in paragraph</title><link>https://sonus.xyz/en/blog/regex-for-parsing-chemical-formulas-in-paragraph/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sonus.xyz/en/blog/regex-for-parsing-chemical-formulas-in-paragraph/</guid><description>Here what it is
Data returns something like this
[ { name: &amp;#34;Water&amp;#34;, details: &amp;#34; water chemical formula is H2O&amp;#34; } ... ] and we want to replace chemical formula to look in html like this
water chemical formula is H2O &amp;lt;p&amp;gt; water chemical formula is H&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;2&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt;O &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt; You can replace the specific content in side the html body like the following.
Link to codepen
var str = &amp;#39;Aluminium oxide or aluminum oxide is a chemical compound of aluminium and oxygen with the chemical formula Al2O3.</description></item><item><title>Toggle-Terminator</title><link>https://sonus.xyz/en/blog/toggle-terminator/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sonus.xyz/en/blog/toggle-terminator/</guid><description>Make Terminator Terminal Act Like Guake/Yakuake Terminal in UBUNTU Many of us might have come across our favourite tools lakes some features, This is something like that turn out to be this repo that implemented a toggle functionality to the terminator.
Check out the git repo :
Star
Install Dependencies
sudo apt-get install xdotool wmctrl Clone the repository
git clone https://github.com/sonus/toggle-terminator.git ~/toggle-terminator Change Directory to toggle-terminator
cd ~/toggle-terminator Make the python script an executable</description></item></channel></rss>