<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pages on Sonus Sundar - Full-stack Software Engineer</title><link>https://sonus.xyz/en/page/</link><description>Recent content in Pages on Sonus Sundar - Full-stack Software Engineer</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sonus.xyz/en/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fixing Heavy JWTs: Bitmasking for Lean &amp; Scalable Permissions</title><link>https://sonus.xyz/en/page/fix-heavy-jwts-bitmasking-scalable-permissions/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sonus.xyz/en/page/fix-heavy-jwts-bitmasking-scalable-permissions/</guid><description>Ever hit a wall with an error message that just screams, &amp;ldquo;Dude, you&amp;rsquo;re sending too much data!&amp;rdquo; Or maybe your shiny, new Single Page Application (SPA) suddenly starts acting weird, requests dropping like flies? Yeah, I&amp;rsquo;ve been there. For us, the culprit turned out to be our good old friend, the JSON Web Token (JWT), specifically when it got absolutely packed with permissions and claims. What started as a neat, efficient way to handle authorization quickly spiraled into a monster that was literally too big for its britches.</description></item><item><title>About Me</title><link>https://sonus.xyz/en/page/about/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sonus.xyz/en/page/about/</guid><description>2022-02-13 I am a curious programmer who loves to learn about something interesting.
Professional Summary Accomplished Software Developer offering 11 years&amp;rsquo; experience in comprehensive design and development of infrastructure and architecture for software projects. Attentive collaborator and communicator from project conception to completion. Creative in devising solutions to improve business operations and meet clients&amp;rsquo; technical needs. Seasoned team leader possessing the technical and interpersonal skills to provide exceptional project deliverables.</description></item></channel></rss>